Politics is riskier for women, there is a double standard.
We usually justify the threats to a mayor by thinking of unpopular choices or poor management,
but analyzing the Italian municipalities, a newly elected female mayor,
three times more likely to experience assaults or threats compared to a man.
It perhaps depends on how the minister sees it, the data says otherwise.
It means that they invest the same resources and guarantee exactly the same quality of services.
So then, with the same results, why do they suffer this disproportionate violence?
It is pure discrimination. They come to pick regardless of how they work,
even when the minister is not clearly better than their colleagues.
The goal is not to influence local laws, but to punish the female figure in power.
A tactic that works. For fear of retaliation, the assaulted administrators almost always give up running for office again.
This is why women struggle to maintain leadership roles.
Today the main problem is not making things easier, but surviving a system that physically tries to push them out.